Oscar Zhou

13 Pigeonwood Lane, Albany, Auckland Central 0211376664 oscarzhou1989@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarzhou1989/

Personal Statement

I worked in China as a C++ developer for one year and a C# developer for two years, working on several commercial projects. Recently, I have been mainly engaged in programing in ASP.NET Framework. In addition to back-end skills, I have mastered some front-end languages, like AngularJS, jQuery, Javascripts. I have a methodical approach to coding and controlling project version.

Key Skills

- Excellent in C++ and C# language and Visual Studio
- An active member of a public speaking association in Auckland
- A strong affinity and career adaptability
- A fast learner and team worker

Project Experience

Data analysis of the price of used cars using Python

(September 2016 – October 2016)

Project Description:

Independent python project. To predict the price of used cars in Auckland according to specific vehicle features, such as model, cc, year and kilometres.

Achievements and responsibilities:

The success rate of the prediction reached 90% in small samples and was successfully applied in selecting a cost-effective used car. The project incorporated data scraping, data integration, data wrangling, data visualization and data analysis and coding.

Financial Audit System

(February 2014 – January 2015)

Project Description:

The project involved developing an internal financial audit system, including the management of a large number of contract documents, the preview of audit reports and the classification of business processes.

Responsibilities:

Demand analysis, front-end and back-end module added and software maintenance.

Medical System

(August 2013 – January 2015)

Project Description:

The project involved developing a system for an American medical alliance to share records of the patients' daily drug use for doctors to carry out drug analysis and research.

Responsibilities:

Update and maintain the established website with C#, integrate the new platform into the original one.

Employment History

ASP.NET Developer, Longway Software Development Co.,Ltd, China (August 2013 – August 2015)

I worked 24 months as a web developer with C#. My main job included:

- Writing both front-end and back-end code of a new module with jQuery and C#.
- Updating and maintaining the existing module and function.

C++ Developer, Tianjin Tiandy Digital Technology Co.,Ltd, China (July 2012 – July 2013)

I worked as a C++ software engineer for one year. The main responsibilities included:

- Updating and maintaining existing Software Development Kit(SDK) with multithreading and socket technology.
- Developing the debugging software for automated testing of the camera circuit board.
- Providing technical support for customers on secondary development based on the SDK.

Education

College/School Name

September 2008 – July 2012 Shenyang Agriculture University (Bachelor Degree) July 2016 – Present Massey University (Postgraudate Diploma, Level 7)